Name: Brian Wheatley

E-Mail: brianwheatley1@hotmail.com

Address: Liverpool (UK)

Qualification: B.Sc. (Hons) Mobile: 07951 367 931

### **Experience Profile:**

Experienced IT Service Delivery Manager with over IT 18 years experience, from those naive 1st line support days to now, managing an entire MSP (managed service provider) has been and continues to be a fantastic journey. I have been fortunate to work collaboratively on large multimillion pound projects across large and complex IT landscapes, right down to the 1-2-1 line management appraisals, my core principles are support the team 1st, followed by a fantastic no blame culture, and always having the customer at the heart of everything we do, in my experience passes the benefit onto the customer.

## Key Information:

- Accountable for ASA firewall patching, anti virus protection and proxy security patching following Microsoft's and SECops best practice governance controls, with test results validation and release management through ITIL change best practice.
- Accountable for all ESXi 6.5 Hyper-V clusters, ensuring 100% availability is maintained and managed.
- Accountable for over 2500, 2016 Windows servers patch management from critical, to a low severity in accordance to SecOps vulnerability evaluation driven from the CVE assessment.
- Accountable for NetApp storage backup and capacity availability management.
- Accountable for annual cyber essentials plus certification.
- Recently attended ISO27001 ISMS auditing foundation course to support re certification, and none compliance reviews with the team and creating action plans to mitigate risks.
- Change Advisory Board (CAB) attend weekly meetings, supporting complex IT organisational changes and project delivery assessments at PMO (project management office)
- Accountable for all product licensing and renewals, both Azure and physical
- Manage and support a 1st 2nd and 3rd line technical function, providing 1-2-1 monthly team and individual performance appraisals, mentoring when required, key man dependency reduction, capability and training plans, the outcome to mitigate all support risks, created a skills matrix and demand management plan with business case improvement plan.
- 10 years 24/7 on call experience from 2nd line fix to enterprise wide service owner
- Accountable for the creation and managing of the company's IT risk register.
- ITSM tooling, call volume trending, and root cause investigation and mitigation, validation of incidents and problems also overall triage management.
- Monthly SLA reporting created and prepared for monthly service reviews.
- Major Incident management support, restoring IT service outages, chairing post incident reviews (PIRs) and lessons learnt and get well plans.
- Transition management.
- Accountable for the company's IT annual disaster recovery process as part of a business continuity strategy.
- Accountable for offshore resourcing delivering against the company's statement of works
- Accountable for 21500 Windows endpoints, scaled at 14000 windows 10, 7 OS, server 20012R 2016/2019, plus 25000 remote networked HP printers held within each VPN'd retail store.
- Supported all new inbound BT network MPLS (PE) changes.
- Review BT open reach MDS change planning, accountable for retails networked GO change decisions based on service risk, estate wide RAG status.
- Payments supplier management with a revenue stream value of 200 million per week turn over Key escalations channel for payments. Under the controls of PCI, FSA and GDPR.
- PRINCE 2 practitioner, ITIL v3 foundation, Agile, CMMI, (CIA Triad awareness)

#### **Technical Qualities:**

- CCNA OSI certified, SCOM certified, Windows 365 project managed, Unix administration, control-m enterprise certified, IBM main frame power7s, CL, working knowledge of AD OU group policy, MS RSS proxy best practice management, MS exchange server, Citrix farm/thick client solid understanding.
- Other tools and experience include certified V8 control-M enterprise systems, BigFix TEM (Tivoli) Netcool, network event management, Nagios, SOX compliance working knowledge (Sarbanes-Oxley), ISeries IBM main frame TN driver coding, windows 2012R 16-19, windows 0365, VLAN, HyperV, ASA Firewal ACLs, ITSM tooling (avanti, Remedy Zendesk (IaaS) (PaaS) (SaaS) appreciation and understanding and further self study.

#### Wider Experience:

- Headed up a project delivery for a recent data centre migration of ESX hosts and NetApp.
- Headed up recent Cyber essentials plus re certification 2019 -2020
- Managed the closure of office/mail 365 migration project, with zero user impact.
- Headed up Mobile project delivery of renewal project.
- Headed up a new service transition work stream adopting ITIL best practice, reducing tech dept to zero.
- Headed up problem reduction workshop and implemented best practices across the client's IT function.
- Headed up real-time monitoring dashboard in supporting improved event management.

- Headed up new SLAs for managed services with more efficient and achievable KPIs
- Attend Weekly project management office meetings (PMO's) supporting retail projects into service.
- Accountable for all IT risk management, risk mitigation. 0
- Regular alignment sessions with partner resourcing, ensuring the business demands are fully supported.
- Third party vendor management through effective discussion, mediation, knowledge transfer and management and collaboration.

# Some key achievements

- Mitigate risk during a firewall change protecting service with a potential multimillion revenue loss
- Introduced a business continuity plan increasing no recorded RTO to 15 minutes.
- Mitigated 98% security level risks to 100% = 400 end points.

  Created 1-year strategic roadmap for 24\*7 reactive monitoring solution helping reduce OPEX by 30K
- MPLS, WBC, TCP/IP, firewall OSPF, protocol awareness supporting national changes
- Increased efficiency drive on disaster recovery RTO/RPO by 50%
- Supported as part of a technical team 2 DCMs for a global payment provider.
- Major incident management of the global cyber-attack WannaCry.
- Headed up Coop Retail's security risk mitigation to over 21500 windows servers, windows 10s 0
- Worked as part of a SLT in reducing inbound incidents by 300%
- Headed up key man dependencies across the entire IT function.

#### Career History:

## Service Delivery Manager - DUK - Career Connect 2018-current

IT Service delivery manager providing the day to day IT operational tasks, managing an enterprise wide infrastructure, ensuring service stability to 100% is maintained. Preparing and creating monthly KPI reports for the client, key escalations channel across all IT services, managing and motivating a 1st 2nd 3rd line support function, driving skills matrix and targeted training plans, advocate of shared knowledge with a no blame culture, manage and approve all IT changes, working closely with external vendors while also addressing any security risks with agreed action plans to mitigate, Plan all project deliveries and transitioning these new services into the live domain. Manage company assets/licensing budgets. Recent project deliveries include, Microsoft azure 365, NetApp, ESX Hyper-V host, mobile phone renewal contracts for all field-based customers. Collaborative effort for ESX hosts and NetApp storage upgrades. Successfully managed the Cyber Essentials Plus re-certification covering 2019-2020.

# Technical Manager/Service Delivery Manager - Coop - 2016 - 2018

Service delivery manager, providing day to day support of all inbound calls supporting 42000 staff nationally, disaster recovery planning, data centre failover recovery planning, 3rd party vendor management, management of the day to day ITSM incidents into the Retail IT space, headed up Retail's IT security patch management governance, IT vulnerability risk mitigation, incident/problem/change management working under the ITIL service framework, enabling and coaching a highly motivated and skilled a 2<sup>nd</sup> 3<sup>rd</sup> team, support their drive to meeting business demands. Wider experience, accountable and service owner of Co-op's (POS Point of sale) Accountable for Coop's tier one enterprise software deployment tool (Tivoli Endpoint Manager, BigFix), Major incident manager for retail distribution and Retail with a pick rate of 12 million cases per day. Headed up Co-op's IT security governance and security patching across 22,500 Windows server and windows 10 endpoints, supported all cloud and on-premise changes, supplier management monthly service reviews with internal and external suppliers driving improved KPIs and security risks to zero.

## IT Operations Manager - Virgin Media - 2014 - 2016

IT Operations manager (contractor support) providing day to day support - ensuring the business is fully supported. Duties consist of change management calls, IA's risk and scoping assessments, chairing team meetings, LEAN objectives with CI mapping, chaired YSWD weekly meetings aiding base camp assessment, KPI's utilising Remedy reporting tools, trend analyst, contract staff 1-2-1's and training and development, Salary validation and timesheets authorisation using Hays API, working in an ITIL environment has enabled me to steer all new processes and map direct ownership utilising the RACI model, helping bolster functional and service support. KPI's, Incident management control of IT operational outages also proving governance for any new services entering the 24\* 7 operations department. Full line manager responsibilities.

## Operation Support Analyst - Virgin Media - 2008- 2014

Fault management, Root cause analysis, Remedy queue management, Various Virgin Media Project engagement and delivery, change management, Validations, delivered process improvement which has enhanced mean time to resolution (MTTR), BAU Duties: CL manipulation, Iseries RPGLE manipulation Iseries Object Movement, copy to import, automation of FTP reports to our internal and external customers' Telnet knowledge. configuration, management and Implementation of Virgin Media's price changes, Billing support and mediation. 24\*7 support of over 100.000.000 process per month, Access Database development, SharePoint Administration. Change management, change engagement. Transition management, UAT in and out of hour's delivery.

### Technical Helpdesk Analyst - Telewest/Virgin Media - 2006 - 2008

Providing a seamless single point of contact across Virgin Media, worked within a tight SLAs environment fault prioritisation. Application Knowledge: provided training to new members of the team, application exposure, Novel Client, Active directory, Microsoft Exchange Server 2003, AS/400 user accounts errors, fault transparency and resolution, with all customers' service. Support Artimus phase 1, 2, 3, & 4 migration, thin and thick client support, WFM (work for management project support. Included 6month Secondment on to DDTV (broadband and telephony provisioning).

#### **Education & Courses:**

# Information Systems with Management (B.Sc., HONS 2:2) - Edge Hill University - 2004

Some key modules include:

- Quality Management
- Unified Modelling Language
- Network Design

## HND Computing (merit) - Edge Hill University - 2002

## A Levels - Knowsley College, 2000

- Pure Math
- ICT

### Maths & English GCSE's (grade C) - Kirkby College - 1995

### Relevant further courses include:

- ITIL, Kepnor Trego, disciplinary grievance training, CMMI, SCUM/Agile, Prince 2 qualified first aider
- Stakeholder management training, Conflict management training
- Cyber Essentials Plus, certification, self learning.
- ISO 27001 internal audit fundamentals certification
- Microsoft Azure 2nd edition essentials (on going)
- Learn Azure in a month of lunches (on going)
- Security cleared.